Guide to the photograph album Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by L. Wells of RAF Hinaidi AD.MC.044
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- From the top left clockwise: Kulav, an Assyrian village, a mountain in Sulav, people within their shelter, people dancing at a wedding, and men and women milking goats., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref29; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Sulav, Kurdistan, Iraq; Agriculture/Farms; Women; Regional/National Dress; Tents; Horses; Animals; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills; Men; Women artists -- Arab countries; Head Covers/Veils; Dancing; Weddings; Events/Occasions; Group Portraits; Boys; Girls; Children; Goats; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq
- Views of Teruanish 'Paradise Alley', mountains, and Haisi in Iraqi Kurdistan., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref30; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Southern Kurdistan, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Iraq; Horses; Animals; Group Portraits; Men; Regional/National Dress
- Views of the RAF camp Ser Amadia, the town and Great Mosque of Amadiya, and the Sulav Waterfall in Iraqi Kurdistan (linked ref158_000004 and linked ref158_000028 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells)., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref31; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Mountains/Hills; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq; Sulav, Kurdistan, Iraq; Tents; Buildings; Waterfalls; Landscapes; Water; Mosques; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq
- Views of the Great Zab River (including the the Pira Bil Bil (sp?) bridge), and surrounds, mountains, the Bahdinan Gate, and a wedding ceremony., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref32; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Bridges; Rivers; Water; Mountains/Hills; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Weddings; Landscapes; Men; Women; Children; Regional/National Dress; Events/Occasions; Dancing; Great Zab River
- From the top left clockwise: an Assyrian home, a woman cooking, a group of Assyrian children, the Great Mosque of Amadiya, an Assyrian village, and a group of men walking down a rocky pass., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref33; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Food; Pottery; Regional/National Dress; Jewelry; Mosques; Buildings; Furnishings; Men; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Girls; Boys; Children; Donkeys; Animals
- Views of the Great Zab River and surrounding mountains in Al-Zab., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref34; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Rivers; Water; Landscapes; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Animals; Great Zab River
- From the top left clockwise: a girl winding wool, two portraits of Kurdish women, a girl grinding corn, an Assyrian man holding a pipe, and a man working on a loom., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref35; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Workers; Tobacco pipes; Smoking; Food; Regional/National Dress; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq; Iraq; Women; Individual Portraits; Girls; Children; Machines; Group Portraits; Men; Facial Hair
- From the top left clockwise: an Assyrian girl, a group of Assyrian children, an Assyrian preacher, a man herding his cattle, two Kurdish woman and child, and the bazaar in Amadiya., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref36; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Markets; English Writing; Girls; Children; Individual Portraits; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Women; Regional/National Dress; Horses; Animals; Group Portraits; Cattle/Cows; Agriculture/Farms; Men; Mountains/Hills; Priests/Clergymen; Facial Hair; Books; Boys
- Views of the Great River Zab in Iraq (linked ref158_000006 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells)., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref37; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Rivers; Water; Mountains/Hills; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq; Iraq; Bridges; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Great Zab River
- A group portrait of the RAF Hinaidi hospital staff including Group Captain H. A. Hewat and a number of Princess Mary's Royal Air Force Nursing Service (PMRAFNS) sisters, 1934; AD_MC_044_ref38; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Nurses; Women; Men; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Doctors
- Views of the hospital wards at RAF Hinaidi, and of the Tigris River from the RAF hospital wards., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref39; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hospitals; Rivers; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Tigris River; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq
- From the top left clockwise: a labourer's camp, a sunset on the Tigris River, the Tigris in Hinaidi, two views of people at the river during the 1935 floods of Hinaidi, and a flock of sheep. (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks.), Circa 1935; AD_MC_044_ref40; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Water; Rivers; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Buildings; Palm Trees; Landscapes; Electricity; Men; Regional/National Dress; Children; Group Portraits; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Sheep; Animals; Agriculture/Farms
- Aerial views of the RAF hospital in Hinaidi, Iraq., Circa 1922 - 1934; AD_MC_044_ref41; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hospitals; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Airplanes; Transportation; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Tigris River; Rivers; Water; Laboratories
- Views of the laboratory at RAF Hinaidi with a portrait of Les Wells in the center and a portrait of lab assistant Zeddam Caliph (linked ref158_000042 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells), and two photographs of laboratory animals used in tests., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref42; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Laboratories; Men; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Lab Coats; Animals; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Scientific Equipment; Electricity
- From the top left clockwise: servicemen and medical staff in the RAF hospital ward, including Brown, Wolf-Corner and Lamb, an operating theatre, the NAAFI canteen, and an X-ray room., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref43; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hospitals; Nurses; Women; Men; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Events/Occasions; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Furnishings; Electricity; Scientific Equipment; Restaurants/bars; Doctors; Christmas; Balloons; Food; Mirrors
- From the top left clockwise: the RAF football team in costumes, a group of servicemen in Baghdad, the RAF band 'The Exiles' including Les Wells on the far right (linked to ref158_000039 in album 'Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection' and AD_MC_046_ref49 in the album 'Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by an RAF serviceman'), and men dressed in costumes (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive imagery) (linked ref158_000039 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells)., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref44; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Costumes; Men; Group Portraits; Christmas; Sports; Baghdad, Iraq; Buildings; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Tuxedos; Performing Arts; Bow Ties; Pianos; Musical Instruments; Hats; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Musicians
- Views of RAF personnel on the "Royal Exodus Hunt" meet in Hinaidi, Iraq., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref45; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Hunting; Dogs; Animals; Royal Air Force; Horses; Electricity; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits; Buildings; Streets/Roads
- Views of the RAF sports teams playing football, hockey, and rugby., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref46; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Sports; Electricity; Group Portraits; Men; Royal Air Force; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- "Top: Views of different plane types including a Westland Wapiti (55B Squadron), a Vickers Vincent, and a Vickers Victoria (70B Squadron). Bottom: Four views of Short Singapore flying boats entitled ""Singapore Flight of Four Flying Boats (one crashed at Messina).""", Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref47; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Airplanes; Transportation; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Tigris River; Rivers; Men; Flags; Uniforms; Palm Trees
- Top: Two Short Singapore flying boats. Bottom: A light armoured car (of uncertain type) and an RAF Rolls Royce armoured car of No.1 Company, RAF Hinaidi Cantonment, Iraq, Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref48; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Weapons; Cars/Trucks; Airplanes; Transportation; Buildings; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Palm Trees; Tigris River; Rivers; Water
- Various species of insects, animals, and plants in Iraq., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref49; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; English Writing; Animals
- A view of a sunset over the Tigris (in flood) from RAF Hinaidi Cantonment, signed with Les Wells' initials (linked ref AD_MC_044_ref40)., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref50; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Palm Trees; Tigris River; Rivers; Water; Signatures; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq
- Menu cards from the RAF hospital cafeteria with the signatures of personnel who were stationed there. From the left to the right: The menu for the farewell dinner, the 1935 Christmas menu, and the 1934 Christmas dinner menu., 1934-1935; AD_MC_044_ref51; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  English Writing; Food; Signatures; Art; Printed Materials; Mosques; Christmas; Royal Air Force; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Religious Sites; Tombs/Mausoleums; Medals/Insignia; Iraq
- The back cover of the album 'A Few Impressions of Iraq.', Circa 1934-1935; AD_MC_044_ref52; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
- A page of an article on a comparative exhibition of busts written for the Illustrated London News., 6 December 1930; AD_MC_044_ref53; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Statues/Sculptures; Newspapers/Magazines; Museums; Newspaper Clippings; Iraq; English Writing
- An article about the reconstruction of the Ishtar Gate in the Pergamon Museum, in the Illustrated London News., 6 December 1930; AD_MC_044_ref54; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Newspapers/Magazines; Newspaper Clippings; Museums; English Writing; Iraq; Architecture; Art
- A map of the Citadel of Babylon., Circa 1934-1935; AD_MC_044_ref55; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Maps; Hillah/al-Ḥillah, Iraq; Printed Materials; English Writing; Temples; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts